<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Reasons humbly offered to the Honourable the House of Commons, by the clothiers of Essex, viz. Colchester, Coxhall, Bocking, Braintree, Witham, and the towns adjacent, against the intended additional duty to be laid upon wines.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 3KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B28773</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99885669</idno>
  <idno type="VID">185499</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2248537140</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing R558F</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 816.m.14[46]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R224804</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99885669</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99885669e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B28773)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 185499)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C1:3[46])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Reasons humbly offered to the Honourable the House of Commons, by the clothiers of Essex, viz. Colchester, Coxhall, Bocking, Braintree, Witham, and the towns adjacent, against the intended additional duty to be laid upon wines.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London? :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1657]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imprint from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Wine and wine making --  Taxation --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Wine and wine making --  Law and legislation --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-06 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-08 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-08 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:185499:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:185499:1"/>
            <head>REASONS humbly offered to the Honourable House of Commons, by the Clothiers of <hi>Essex,</hi> viz. <hi>Colchester, Coxhall, Bocking, Braintree, Witham,</hi> and the Towns adjacent, against the in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended Additional Duty to be laid upon <hi>Wines.</hi>
            </head>
            <p n="1">1. AS our Bays, Says, Perpetuanos, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> go Nine Tenths of them to <hi>Portugal</hi> and <hi>Spain,</hi> if a new Impositi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on be laid upon Wines, the King of <hi>Portugal</hi> (we cannot but reasonably expect) then will prohibit our Manufacture, having had an instance of the like; which will prove fatal to us as the stagnation of the Blood.</p>
            <p n="2">2. It will totally destroy the Woollen Manufactury of <hi>Essex,</hi> for 50 or 60000 Families, as Spinsters, Weavers, and Combers, who are employed therein; and have no other Em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployments whereby to get a livelyhood, will be inevitably all Ruined, by reason those Tradesmen who employ the Poor, will be forced to lay by their Trades.</p>
            <p n="3">3. When these Families have no Employment, the Lands of the County cannot maintain the Poor; and what the Poor will do for maintenance, we humbly Pray the Wisdom of this House to take into their Consideration.</p>
            <p n="4">4. We humbly Pray, That if the Wisdom of this House will lay a new Imposition upon Wines; That those Farmers may be obliged upon the Penalty of 100000 <hi>l.</hi> or give such Security as this Honourable House shall think fit, to buy those Goods that are now upon Tradesmens hands, at such Rates as the Merchants at this time will give, and oblige themselves to buy the same quantities of our Manufacture for Four Years ensuing, as has been sold for Four Years last past, to prevent the Ruine of so many Thousand Families.</p>
            <p n="5">5. We believe by the Importation of <hi>Spanish</hi> and <hi>Portugal</hi> Wines, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> since the Prohibition of <hi>French</hi> Wines, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> the Exportation of all our Manufacturies have been near one Third part increased; which hath the better enabled us chear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully to bear our proportion of Taxes, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> in the carrying on the present War hitherto, which we can give no other Reason for, but from the Benefit the Native Subjects of <hi>Spain</hi> and <hi>Portugal</hi> reap, by our Merchants bringing Returns, in the Fruits of those Countries, which formerly came from <hi>France;</hi> and were not the Product of our Manufacturies, but of our Monies.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:185499:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:185499:2"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>